yo how's it going everybody
welcome back it's been a while since i
posted and uh i thought i'd start a new
series on uh girl player world scripting
so i figured i'd just start making a
couple videos because there's not a
whole lot you know on them so uh for
today's video we're just gonna get right
into it and
assuming you have access to some sort of
uh server to script on whether that's
you know
let's just say like one of the dev
servers or one that you make yourself
let's just start off by creating a
weapon so
when in grail uh you have a weapon which
is attached to a player so they'll have
access to whatever is on them so let's
just create something called
player slash
bomb so let's make a script that places
a bomb
so one of the first things you're going
to need to understand with gs2 is client
side and server side
on the outside so whatever is below this
exactly like this i know it's commented
out but it just works whatever below is
happening on the client itself and
whatever above is happening on the
server
so you there's a lot of things you're
going to want to do on the server for
security reasons so when you're dealing
with like health
uh maybe custom movements and stuff but
um you know money all that all that kind
of things that needs to be secured but
when you're just doing some basic
processing client sides should be pretty
good
so let's make a bond script that this
player is going to have in their
inventory here
so first off we need to give it to
ourselves so let's just do it the lazy
way so you're going to want to do
something called find player which is a
function
then
this right here is where you're gonna
put your uh account id so i have a
community name which is chad master so
i'll do that and then you're gonna wanna
add the weapon
and then
um
so we're gonna be referring to this dot
name which is this refers to whatever
object it is which is the player bomb
and then dot name is one of the
attributes so it'll just be the name so
it's itself
so it should just add it to me right
away
um something i also wanted to do was
let's just use the f key which is a key
code 70 which i already know so let's
make that a constant key underscore f
and let's set that to 70.
so i just made a variable that's
constant so this will never change never
change because it'll always be 70.
so now in order to actually get this to
work you need to create a function so
let's um
let's use let's just use the grail
control on key down so function
and then grail
control
that on e
down
and then let's open this up
and then as a parameter let's pass the
key code since that's what we're
actually using so now whenever
whenever a button is down we're going to
get that key code
so now we can do something with that so
let's say we want to
take this this concept we have which is
pressing f
so they have that equipped if they press
f what are we going to want to do
something we need to do is well let's
test it out let's do player.chat let's
reference the player object
in programming this is how it works and
then we're going to use a period
and then we're going to take the
attribute chat which is created which is
in the just the client itself so you'll
have to learn you know the other ones
like their positioning and stuff so
let's just say
dropping a bomb
okay let's save that and let's hope that
i added it to myself
okay so it didn't so i need to use my
community name which is or my id
so let's do this
there we go so now player
okay
boy i already have a script but
anytime you press a key code it's going
to do that so let's do this actually so
if
and let's create some brackets here
let's take a chat
paste it in here
so now what's your if statement b it
should be if the key code
equal to
e code f
save that and actually let me
open the weapons let me remove
this one right here i already have
another script doing that okay so now we
have the bomb right so we press f
we're dropping a bomb
so now that's working so now let's do
let's drop a bomb
so in grail and player rolls itself
there's already a
predefined function which is put bomb
and then inside of here
let's place zero
and the player.x
and the player
so now we're basically dropping a bomb
wherever the player x in the player y is
so that should place it right on
ourselves
so let's press f dropping a bomb
and now we have a bomb
so really easy
you know the biggest thing in gs2 is
learning you know the built-in functions
and all the parameters and the things it
takes in and also understanding what
should be on client side and what should
be on server side
so
there's a lot of other things you can do
so right now it's just placing it in the
top left corner because that's x and y
zero
um so we can change that we can look at
the player's direction so we can even
just say instead of dropping a bomb
let's concatenate with an at sign or a
space like this
let's concatenate the player dot
direction
okay so now see how i'm facing two then
i'm facing three
and one
and zero okay so now you can control
which you know if they're facing this
way place the bomb in front of them
so uh we can do that quick but you know
i think that you should try and do that
try and
try and create some more if statements
based on the direction so if the
direction
is right which is three
create an if statement just like that
i'll give you a little hint
so if
if player dot direction is equal to
three then you're going to want to
do this
let's take the bomb
oh wait you probably want to embed this
inside
of them pressing f
so
if the direction is three
then
we want to foot bomb
[Music]
room
y
so now
if they're facing three
there we go i just had a little error in
there so now if they're facing three
place a bomb they're facing two one or
zero it does not place a bomb so now
what i want you guys to do for you to
learn is let's say they do point they do
face this direction
which what should the x and y be should
you increase should you increase the x
here
by let's just say 10
um for this direction see how it's
placing in front but it should probably
be smaller than that
now look at this
let's just do i don't know maybe three
so now if they're facing this direction
it places it three and then maybe we
subtract a little bit of y
that might be too much oh we need to add
maybe two
okay we want to do one
there we go perfect
so now this direction no bomb this
direction no bomb this direction no bomb
and when we press this direction we
place a bomb
so now how about you guys
you know since you're learning how much
you guys finish the script up i'll let
you
copy it here
and then what i want you guys to do is
finish the directions make sure that
they can
um
place a bomb in every direction so it's
not just on the player you should be
able to do this by
i'll give you a hint all you want to do
is change some of the
the directions here because you're just
adding on to it so it's you know updated
but i think that's it for this this
video um if you guys want more videos on
gs2 there's not a whole lot of them so i
i will be willing to go as deep as i can
and cover everything um i'll put the
wiki docs in the description if you're
new and you know you want to look
through them
other than that i could probably make
more videos just comment and let me know
so this is just the first one and i
think it's pretty solid we can uh talk
about other things like flags and
server flags and npcs like right now we
just created a weapon script here's a
class and here's an npc
so just let me know in the comments if
you guys want to learn more i can try
and cover as much as i know so thanks
for watching make sure to subscribe and
i'll see you next time